(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
凡打全部の子持ちっ子
Fly ball, all the kids with children
エブリスタンス健常
Every stance, healthy
立石不満もまなみとあれに ハードでツッコミ！
Even Tateishi's dissatisfaction, with Manami and that... hard poke!
ぽいっサボテズに合体
Toss! Combine with the cacti
キャンパス勝手に安泰
Campus, peace of mind at will
リハ察スカンザ身を交せば
If I dodge the rehearsal's scout instantly...
ミツバチオンパレード！
...bees on parade!
ネチョリーナポリタン無作法リミタイだ
Sticky Napolitan, it's a rude limit-out
笑った間にエガパスがマニア
Occasionally laughed, Egapas is a mania
パン！ツ！出っかてぃ！
Pants! Are out!
叩け来なきゃ！
Hit it, gotta come!
K・P・I・T・G・B・ばり・GO・ツー・カー！
K-P-I-T-G-B-Very-GO-Two-Car!
くるぶし決めてマッパスタンス
Fixed ankles, naked stance
踏んで飛ばす手枷乱装
Step and fly, shackles, chaotic equipment
性癖寒天感電に沸くアイツを
That guy who boils in sexual fetishes and agar electrocution...
引いて悦感微かに足掻く
...pulling back, feelings of pleasure, faintly struggling
チョクサビだ！飛ばせ目暗そ！
Straight hook! Fly, dazzle them!
成獣ナビカス全卵オーガニズム僕！
Adult beast, Navi-scum, whole egg, organism, Me!
ヘッチャラ！
I don't care!
愛情終わり周期闇
Love ends, periodic darkness
ヘッチャラ！
I don't care!
マスコミ参加恒例エジキさ
Mass media participation, the usual, it's prey
解放パッー！てぃー！
Release, party!
安！安！てぃー！
Anti! Anti!
S・S・痛みがせい！
S-S-Pain is the cause!
アンタドレー！
You're a slave!
お前ドレー！
暴走禁止モード発生！
Rampage forbidden mode activated!
動向退
Trends, retreat
困退
Trouble, retreat
DEATH JUST A WAR
踊れ己がヘッチャラ！
Dance, your own 'I don't care!'
爪 爪 爪 常にオナキッズ
Nails, nails, nails, always onanists
惚れず狂わして濡らすがいい
Go crazy without falling in love, just let it get wet
爪 爪 爪 うんざりオナキッズ
Nails, nails, nails, fed up, onanists
オーブス転がして逃がれ
Rolling orbs, escape
…濡らすがいい
...should get wet
放り狂わして濡らすがいい
Let it go crazy and get wet
GO!
本家失富も袋　エムルだ剃手錠
廟とぞそ蛇尾はと　梓馬見詰まる朧
Even if it's the original house, it's a bag, an emerald shaving handcuff.
A mausoleum and then the snake's tail, the catalpa horse staring at the haze.
摂理パタリヤ　ドブリピタピタ
彼方ダミヤ　コボンコボリヤ
Providence Patariya, Doburi Pitapita,
Beyond Damiya, Kobon Koboriya.
落着け歌舞伎　詰まってオナキ
ピピインビキミ　秘密ゴツゴツ
Calm down Kabuki, stuck and crying,
Pipii-in Bikimi, secret ruggedness.
GO! GO!
I want to want to の天地 waste you
超待ちモンペットマッチョ
怖いのご賞手沙汰にご安心
身読素炎上炎上
I want to want to, heaven and earth waste you,
Super waiting monpet macho,
Rest assured of the fearful verdict,
Mind reading burning burning.
即ソビだ　唾木寝ぐら
便器乗り出す　そっと産み出す　これぞ必殺
Immediately Soviet, salivary wood nest,
Leaning out of the toilet, gently birthing, this is the finishing move.
ちょっと神々金子と真似合点しカセボーイ
国ごと潰すか滅ぼすか
便器実子混沌の魔崩
値切り厳禁金座でヘッド
Wait, the gods Kaneko and the imitation point, Kase-boy,
Crush the whole country or destroy it,
The toilet child of chaos magic collapse,
No haggling, head at the gold seat.
狂い狂わせ奴と意思　えそえそと闇がせ
あんとドレイ　お前ドレイ
抗争消しもう怒発生
Going crazy, letting them go crazy, the will of that guy,
Mimicking the darkness,
And Slave, You Slave,
The conflict is gone, anger is bursting.
BOBO-CHA! BOBO-CHA! フベストゥスタトー
BOBO-CHA! BOBO-CHA! Full best start!
踊れ己等　ヘファスマ
Dance, you all! Hefasuma!
慌ただ死め詰めて　TOO MANY ONNA-KISS
Frantically squeezing to death, TOO MANY ONNA-KISS
放り狂わして濡らすがいい
Let it go crazy and get wet
シメシメシメンで ONNA-KISS
Squeeze, squeeze, squeeze in the ONNA-KISS
汚物転がして濡るがいい
Roll the filth and get wet
放り狂わして濡らすがいい
Let it go crazy and get wet
餓死縁勧聴が鉛　独り座せ仄暗い
全て引掻くその癖　誰のアイデア抑制
Starvation leads to lead, sitting alone in the dim light,
That habit of scratching everything, whose idea is suppressed.
ビシッ！　本バチは開けない
シシッ！　ぐちょぐちょになって
完済！　六感でロッカ
やるだびまるし
Snappy! The real drumsticks won't open,
Ssshh! Getting all mushy,
Paid off! Lock with the sixth sense,
Do it over and over.
We know will freezing, freezing, freezing, freezing
まつるぞーー！
Let's festival!!
踊れ己等　ヘファスマ
Dance, you all! Hefasuma!
慌ただ死め詰めて　TOO MANY ONNA-KISS
放り狂わして濡らすがいい
Frantically squeezing to death, TOO MANY ONNA-KISS
Let it go crazy and get wet
シメシメシメンで ONNA-KISS
汚物転がして濡るがいい
Squeeze, squeeze, squeeze in the ONNA-KISS
Roll the filth and get wet
放り狂わして濡らすがいい　GO!
Let it go crazy and get wet. GO!
はぁ、こんなに頑張ってるのに…
Ah, even though we're working this hard...
誰も聴いてくれないね。
Nobody's listening to us.
悲しいよ…
It's so sad...
あたしたち才能ないのかな…
Maybe we just don't have talent...
一生懸命なのに…
Even though we're doing our best...
よかったぺこだよ！
It was great, peko!
感動した！
I was moved!
あ！　あなたは…
Ah! You are...
学年一歌が上手い、不知火フレアさん！
The one who is the best singer in our grade, Shiranui Flare-san!
どうも。
Hello.
そしてあなたは、うさ耳が生えていることでかなりの集客効果がある、兎田ぺこらさん！
And you are Usada Pekora-san, who has a huge audience because of those rabbit ears!
どうも。
Hello.
ねぇ…
Hey...
よかったら…
If you'd like...
一緒にバンド！
Join our band!
え？！
Eh?!
そうして月日は流れ
And so, months passed
過酷な練習を乗り越えた4人は
Overcoming harsh practice sessions, the four of them
文化祭のステージに立つのであった
Stood on the stage of the culture festival!
キミを見てるといつもハート　ドキドキ
When I look at you, my heart always goes pit-a-pat
揺れる想いはマシュマロみたいに　ふわふわ
My swaying feelings are light and fluffy like marshmallows
いつもがんばる
Always doing my best
キミの横顔
Your profile
ずっと見てても気づかないよね
Even if I keep watching you, you won't notice, will you?
夢の中なら
If it's inside a dream
ふたりの距離
The distance between us
縮められるのにな
I could shorten it, though
ああ　カミサマお願い
Oh God, please
ふたりだけのドリームタイムください
Give us a dream time just for the two of us
お気に入りのうさちゃん抱いて
Hugging my favorite stuffed bunny
今夜もおやすみ
Good night tonight as well
ふわふわタイム　ふわふわタイム　ふわふわタイム
Light and fluffy time, light and fluffy time, light and fluffy time
ふとした仕草に今日もハートときめき
At a casual gesture, my heart goes pit-a-pat again today
さりげない笑顔お向かい道すぎて Oh-Oh-Baby
A casual smile, passing you on the street, Oh-Oh-Baby
いつだって未知だったね (未知だったね)
It was always unknown (always unknown)
君のまじか (君のまじか) 瞳閉じても 浮かんでくるよ
Right next to you (right next to you), even if I close my eyes, you appear
夢でいいから (夢でいいから) 二人だけの
Even if it's just a dream (even if it's just a dream), I want our...
Sweet time ほしいの
...Sweet time
ああ 神様 お願い 好きになるほど
Ah, God, please, the more I like you...
Dreaming night 切ないの
...the more this Dreaming night becomes painful
とっておきのくまちゃんですし
With my special teddy bear...
今夜は大丈夫さ
...I'll be okay tonight
もう少し勇気 振って 自然に話せば
If I could muster a little more courage and talk naturally...
何かが変わるのかな
Maybe something would change?
そんな気がするけど
I feel that way
だけどそれが一番難しいのよ
But that's the hardest part of all
話のきっかけとか どうしようって
Thinking about how to start a conversation...
段取り考えてる 時点でもう
The moment I'm planning it out...
自然じゃないよね
...it's not natural anymore
ああ もういいよ
Ah, enough already!
めちゃ! めちゃめちゃめちゃ!
Mecha! Mecha-mecha-mecha!
ああ 神様 お願い 一度だけの
Ah, God, please, just give me...
ミラクルタイムください
...a miracle time just once
もしすんなり話せれば そのあとは
If I can talk smoothly, then after that...
永遠になれるよで
...we can be together forever
God knows...
作詞：畑 亜貴　作曲：神前 暁
Lyrics: Aki Hata  Composition: Satoru Kosaki
乾いた心で駆け抜ける
I run through with a parched heart
ごめんね何もできなくて
I'm sorry I can't do anything
痛みを分かち合うことさえ
Even sharing the pain...
あなたは許してくれない
...you won't allow me to
無垢に生きるため振り向かず
To live in innocence, without looking back...
背中向けて去ってしまう On the lonely rail
...you turn your back and leave, on the lonely rail
私ついていくよ どんな辛い世界の闇の中でもさえ
I will follow you, even in the darkness of a harsh world
きっとあなたは輝いて
I'm sure you will shine
超える未来の果て 弱さゆえに魂こわされるように
Beyond the end of the future, as if my soul is being broken by my weakness
My way 重なるよ 今
My way overlaps now
二人に God bless...
God bless the two of us...
届けて熱くなる思いは
Deliver it, these burning feelings
現実溶かして彷徨う
Wandering while melting reality
会いたい気持ちに理由はない
There's no reason for wanting to see you
あふれだす想いも
Even these overflowing feelings
すべてを 美しき夢だけを
Everything, only the beautiful dream
描きながら 追いかけよう for your lonely heart
As I draw it, let's chase it for your lonely heart
やめて 嘘はあなたらしくないよ
Stop it, lies aren't like you
目を見て これからのことを話そう
Look into my eyes, let's talk about the future
私 覚悟してる
I'm prepared
暗い未来だって 強くなって
Even if it's a dark future, I'll become stronger
運命変えられるかもね my wish
Maybe I can change destiny, my wish
かなえたいのに 全ては...
I want it to come true, but everything is...
あなたがいて
Because you are here
私がいて
Because I am here
他の人は 消えてしまった
Everyone else has disappeared
淡い夢の 美しさを
The beauty of a faint dream
描きながら
As I draw it
傷跡 なぞる
I trace the scars
だから 私 付いていくよ
So, I will follow you
どんな辛い 世界の闇の中でも
No matter how painful it is in the darkness of the world
きっと あなたは輝いて
Surely, you will shine
超える未来の果て
Beyond the end of the future
弱さゆえに 魂こわされるように
As if my soul is being broken due to weakness
my way 重なるよ
My ways overlap
いま 二人に God bless...
Now, for the two of us, God bless...
文化祭終わったねー！
The culture festival is over!
終わったー！最高だったー！
It's over! It was the best!
ねぇみんな、あのさ、今度はさ、もう学校なんて狭い箱は飛び出さない？
Hey everyone, listen, next time, why don't we jump out of this small box called school?
おっ？どうしたの？どこ行っちゃうの？
Oh? What's up? Where are we going?
路上に行こう、路上に！
Let's go to the streets, the streets!
じゃあみんな、次は私服で集合ね！
Then everyone, let's meet in our casual clothes next!
またねー！バイバーイ！
See you! Bye-bye!
準備しとくペコら！パイセン！
I'll get ready-peko! Senpai!
あーお待たせー！
Ah, sorry for the wait!
お疲れー！
Good job!
今日、頑張ろう！
Let's do our best today!
頑張ろうー！
Let's do our best!
こいつ、私服がこれってマジか？
Is she serious that this is her casual clothes?
大丈夫？痛くない？やる？やる？やる？
Are you okay? Does it hurt? Shall we do it? Shall we? Shall we?
やるやる！やろっか！
Let's do it! Let's do it!
頑張ろうね！
Let's do our best!
頑張ろうー！
Pretender
作詞・作曲：藤原 聡
Lyrics/Composition: Satoshi Fujihara
君とのラブストーリー それは予想通り
The love story with you, it's just as expected
いざ始まれば ひとり芝居だ
Once it starts, it's a one-man show
ずっとそばにいたって 結局ただの観客だ
Even if I'm always by your side, in the end, I'm just a spectator
感情のないアイム・ソーリー それはいつも通り
A soulless "I'm sorry", it's just like usual
慣れてしまえば 悪くはないけど
If I get used to it, it's not so bad, but...
君とのロマンスは人生柄 続きはしないことを
The romance with you, given my life, I knew it wouldn't continue...
知った
...I knew that
もっと違う設定で
With a different setting
もっと違う関係で
With a different relationship
...で 出会える世界線
...in a worldline where we meet.
選べたらよかった もっと違う性格で
I wish I could've chosen it, with a different personality.
もっと違う価値観で
With a different set of values.
愛を伝えられたらいいな
I wish I could've expressed my love.
そう願っても無駄だから
But even if I wish for that, it's futile.
Goodbye 君の運命の人は僕じゃない
Goodbye, the one destined for you isn't me.
辛いけど否めない でも離れ難いのさ
It's painful but undeniable, yet it's hard to let go.
その髪に触れただけで 痛いや いやいや
Just touching your hair, it hurts, no, no, no.
でも甘いな いやいや Goodbye
But it's sweet, no, no, goodbye.
それじゃ僕にとって君は何？
Then, what are you to me?
答えは分からない 分かりたくもないのさ
I don't know the answer, and I don't want to know.
たった一つ確かなことが あるとするのならば
If there's only one thing for certain,
君は綺麗だ
You are beautiful.
誰かが偉そうに語る 恋愛の論理
Some logic of love that someone talks about so pompously,
何一つとしてピンとこなくて
None of it really clicks for me.
飛行機の窓から見下ろした
It's like looking down from an airplane window
知らない街の夜景みたいだ
At the night view of an unknown city.
もっと違う設定で もっと違う関係で
In a different setting, in a different relationship,
出会える世界線 選べたらよかった
I wish I could've chosen a worldline where we met.
いたって純な心で 叶った恋を抱きしめて
With a very pure heart, holding onto a love that came true,
「好きだ」とか無責任に言えたらいいな
I wish I could say "I love you" so irresponsibly.
そう願っても虚しいのさ
But even if I wish for that, it's hollow.
Goodbye つないだ手の向こうに エンドライン
Goodbye, an end-line beyond our joined hands.
引き伸ばすたびに 疼きだす未来には
In the future that starts to ache every time I prolong it,
君はいない その事実に 痛いや いやいや
You aren't there. Facing that fact, it hurts, no, no, no.
それじゃ苦しいよな
That would be painful, wouldn't it?
Goodbye 君の運命の人は僕じゃない
Goodbye, the one destined for you isn't me.
辛いけど否めない でも離れ難いのさ
It's painful but undeniable, yet it's hard to let go.
その髪に触れただけで 痛いや いやいや
Just touching your hair, it hurts, no, no, no.
子でも甘いな いやいや Goodbye
But it's sweet, no, no, goodbye.
それじゃ僕にとって君は何？
Then, what are you to me?
答えは分からない 分かりたくもないのさ
I don't know the answer, and I don't want to know.
たった一つ確かなことが あるとするのならば
If there's only one thing for certain,
君は綺麗だ
You are beautiful.
それも分かってるんだ
I know that too.
とても綺麗だ
You are very beautiful.
天使にふれたよ！
作詞：稲葉エミ 作曲：川口進
Tenshi ni Fureta yo! (We touched an Angel!)
Lyrics: Emi Inaba Composition: Susumu Kawaguchi
ねえ 思い出の欠片に
Hey, if I were to name...
名前をつけて保存するなら
...the fragments of our memories and save them...
「宝物」がぴったりだね
..."Treasure" would be the perfect name.
そう 心の容量が
Yeah, we spent so much time together...
いっぱいになるくらいに過ごしたね
...that my heart's capacity is almost full.
ときめき色の毎日
Every day was colored with excitement.
なじんだ制服と上履き
Our familiar uniforms and indoor shoes.
思い出がいっぱい
So many memories
明日の意味 口に
Speaking of tomorrow's meaning
置いてかなくちゃいけないのかな
I wonder if I have to leave it behind
でもね、会えたよ！
But you know, I met one!
素敵な天使に
A wonderful angel
卒業は終わりじゃない
Graduation isn't the end
これからも仲間だから
Because we'll always be friends
一緒の写真たち
The photos we took together
おそろのキーホルダー
Our matching keychains
いつまでも輝いてる
They'll shine forever
ずっと その笑顔 ありがとう
For that smile, always, thank you
君たち、あんまり上手くないね。
You guys aren't very good, are you?
え？
Eh?
でも、すごく楽しそうだったよ。
But you looked like you were having a lot of fun.
何、このおじさん？
Who is this old guy?
何？誰？
What? Who?
不審者？
A suspicious person?
僕の事務所に入らないかい？
Would you like to join my agency?
えーーー！？
Ehhh!?
う、嘘！これ、これってスカウト！？
N-No way! Is this... is this a scout!?
メジャーデビューぺこ！？
A major debut, peko!?
メジャーデビュー！？
A major debut!?
やったーーー！！
We did it!!
Crow Song
廃校にはシャッターの壁
The closed school has walls of shutters
指先は鉄の匂い
My fingertips smell like iron
進め、弾け、どの道混むでしょう
Go forth, burst open, either way it'll be crowded
Fly away ここから
Fly away from here
凡な 奴らが
Ordinary people like us
Love を 奏でろ
Play love
Love を 見据えろ
Gaze at love
息さえできない 街の中
In a town where I can't even breathe
星空が 最高の舞台
The starry sky is the best stage
カラスたちが カカと鳴くよ
The crows are cawing away
いつも思うよ いつ寝てるんだろう
I always wonder, when do they ever sleep?
Fly away 私も
Fly away, I too
そっと 歌うよ
I'll sing softly
Love を響かせ
Let love ring out
そっと 歌うよ
I'll sing softly
いつまでこんなところにいる
How long will you stay in a place like this?
そう言う奴もいた気がする
I feel like someone once said that
うるさいことだけ言うのなら
If you're only going to say annoying things
漆黒の羽にさらわれて
Be swept away by jet-black wings
消えていけ
Fade away
全力でも倒れそうだ
I feel like I might collapse even with full effort
指先 擦り切れて 痛い
My fingertips are frayed and hurting
でもね やるよ 今夜も熱いストーリー
But I'll do it, tonight too, a hot story
Fly away ここから
Fly away from here
凡な 奴らが
Ordinary people like us
Love を 奏でろ
Play love
Love を 歌うよ
I'll sing love
いつまでだってここにいるよ
I'll be here forever
通り過ぎてゆく人の中
Among the people passing by
闇に閉ざされたステージで
On a stage closed in darkness
今 希望の歌 歌うよ
Now, I'll sing a song of hope
あなただって疲れてるでしょう
You must be tired too, right?
その背中にも届けたいよ
I want to reach that back too
こんな暗闇の中から
From within this darkness
希望 照らす 光の歌を
A song of light that illuminates hope
その歌を
That song
星座になれたら
If I Could Become a Constellation
真っ暗 街は 6時
Pitch black town at 6 o'clock
もうそこに 一番星
Already there, the first star
影を踏んで 夜に紛れたくなる 帰り道
Stepping on shadows, wanting to be lost in the night on the way home
どんなに探してみても
No matter how much I look
ひとつしかない星
The one and only star
何万光年 離れたところから あんなに輝く
Shining like that from tens of thousands of light-years away
いいな 君は みんなから愛されて
Must be nice, you, being loved by everyone
いいや 僕は ずっと一人きりさ
Nah, I've always been all alone
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
星降る夜 一瞬の願いごと
A starry night, a fleeting wish
きらめいて ゆらめいて 震えてるシグナル
Sparkling, swaying, a trembling signal
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
空見上げて指を差されるような
Like being pointed at while looking up at the sky
繋いだ線 ほどかないで
Don't undo the connected line
僕が...
I...
どんなに眩しくても
No matter how bright it is
まっすぐ 時計は ８時
The clock is straight at 8 o'clock
夜空に待ってんの　星
Stars waiting in the night sky
何光年離れたところには
Millions of light-years away
もう無いかもしれない
They might not even be there anymore
月が嫌いで 泣きそうになるのは
The reason I hate the moon and feel like crying
いつの日にか 別れが来るから
Is because one day, we'll have to part
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
彗星みたいな流れる独り言
A flowing monologue like a comet
消えてゆく残像は 真夜中のプリズム
The fading afterimage is a midnight prism
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
切なる願いが誰かに届いたら
If my earnest wish reached someone
変われるかな
I wonder if I can change
夜の淵をなぞるような こんな僕でも
Even someone like me who traces the edge of the night
はるか彼方 僕ら出会ってしまった
In the far distance, we happened to meet
カルマだから 何度も出会ってしまうよ
Because it's karma, we'll meet again and again
雲の隙間で
Between the gaps of the clouds
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
夜広げて描こうよ空言
Let's spread out the night and draw fabrications
暗闇を照らすような 満月じゃなくても
Even if it's not a full moon that lights up the darkness
だから集まって星座になりたい
That's why I want us to gather and become a constellation
色とりどりの光放つような
One that emits multicolored lights
繋いだ線　解かないよ
I won't let go of the connected lines
君がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how bright you are
無事にメジャーデビューし 羽ばたく4人
Successfully making their major debut, the four take flight
時に支え合い
Supporting each other at times
あ、ここは、からの、こう、こう
Ah, from here, then, like this, and this
あー、OK OK
Ah, okay okay
いい、いい、いい
Good, good, good
せーの、で！
Ready, go!
じゃあ、船長は...
Then, the Captain will...
大丈夫！？
Are you okay!?
時にケンカし
Quarreling at times
見てフレア、ちゃんと、目！ 目！ 目！
Look Flare, look properly, eyes! Eyes! Eyes!
仲良くして、仲良く
Get along, get along
嫌って言ってるでしょ、ぺこちゃん
I said no, Peko-chan
ねぇ、お願いだって
Hey, I'm asking you
嫌だって、やらないといけない
I said no, but we have to do it
もうー、お願い！
Jeez, please!
嫌ー！
No!
そして
And then
最後(不穏)の舞台へ
To the final (unsettling) stage
午前二時 踏切に 望遠鏡を 担いでった
2 AM at the railroad crossing, I carried my telescope
ベルトに 結んだ ラジオ 雨は 降らないらしい
Radio tied to my belt, they said it wouldn't rain
二分後 君が来た 大袈裟な 荷物背負ってきた
Two minutes later, you arrived, carrying an exaggerated amount of luggage
始めようか 天体観測 ほうき星を 探して
Shall we begin our celestial observation, searching for a comet?
深い 闇に 飲まれないように 精一杯 歌った
I sang with all my might so as not to be swallowed by the deep darkness
君の 震える 手を 握ろうとした あの日は
That day when I tried to hold your trembling hand
見えないものを 見ようとして 望遠鏡を...
Trying to see things that can't be seen, peering through the telescope...
天体観測
Stargazing
...ほうき星を待っている
...waiting for a comet
望遠鏡を覗き込んだ
I looked through my telescope
静寂を切り裂いて いくつも声が生まれたよ
Tearing through the silence, many voices were born
明日が僕らを呼んだって 返事もろくにしなかった
Even if tomorrow called us, we didn't even answer
今というほうき星 君と二人追いかけていた
That comet called "now", I was chasing it with you
Oh yeah, ah...
気がつけばいつだって ひたすら何か探している
I realized I'm always searching for something
幸せの定義とか 悲しみの置き場とか
The definition of happiness, or a place for sadness
生まれたら死ぬまで ずっと探してるさ
From birth to death, I'll be searching forever
始めようか天体観測 ほうき星をさがして
Let's start our stargazing, searching for a comet
今まで見つけたものは 全部覚えている
I remember everything I've found so far
君の震える手を 握れなかった痛みも
Even the pain of not being able to hold your trembling hand
知らないものを知ろうとして 望遠鏡を覗き込んだ
Trying to know the unknown, I looked through my telescope
暗闇を照らすような 微かな光探したよ
I searched for a faint light that would light up the darkness
そして知った痛みを 今だに僕は覚えている
And the pain I learned then, I still remember it even now
今というほうき星 今も一人追いかけている
That comet called "now", I'm still chasing it alone even now
Oh yeah, ah...
背が伸びるにつれて 伝えたい事も増えてった
As I grew taller, the things I wanted to say increased
宛名のない手紙も 崩れるほど重なった
Even the letters without addresses piled up until they collapsed
僕は元気でいるよ 心配事も少ないよ
I'm doing well, I have few worries
ただ一つ今も 思い出すよ
Except just one thing I still remember now
予報外れの雨に 打たれて泣き出しそうな
Struck by unexpected rain, looking like you're about to cry
君の震える手を 握れなかったあの日を
The day I couldn't hold your trembling hand
見えてるものを見落として 望遠鏡をまた担いで
Overlooking what was visible, I shouldered my telescope again
静寂と暗闇の 帰り道を駆け抜けた
I ran through the way home of silence and darkness
そして知った痛みが 今だに僕を支えている
And the pain I learned then is still supporting me now
今というほうき星 今も一人追いかけている
That comet called "now", I'm still chasing it alone even now
もう一度君に会おうとして 望遠鏡をまた担いで
Trying to meet you once more, I shouldered my telescope again
前と同じ午前二時 踏切まで駆けてくよ
Just like before at 2 AM, I'll run to the railroad crossing
始めようか天体観測 二分後に君が来なくとも
Let's start our stargazing, even if you don't come in two minutes
今というほうき星 君と二人追いかけている
That comet called "now", I'm chasing it with you
Oh yeah, ah...
ありがとー！
Thank you!
あつーいねー！
It's hot, isn't it!
あつーい！最高！
It's hot! The best!
熱いと言ったらー？
When we say "hot", then...?
水着ー！！
Swimsuits!!
こんなに立派になって...
You've become so grand...
やっぱり君たちは最高だよ。
You guys really are the best.
小さな恋のうた
A Small Love Song
広い宇宙の数ある一つ
One of many in the vast universe
青い地球の広い世界で
In the wide world of the blue Earth
小さな恋の思いは届く
A small love's feelings reach
小さな島のあなたのもとへ
To you on a small island
あなたと出会い 時は流れる
Meeting you, time flows
思いを込めた 手紙も増える
The letters filled with my feelings increase
いつの間にか二人響く
Before we knew it, we both resonate
時に激しく 時に切なく
Sometimes intensely, sometimes painfully
響くは遠く はるか彼方へ
Resonating far, to the distant beyond
優しい歌は 世界を変える
A gentle song changes the world
ほら あなたにとって大事な人ほど
Look, the more important someone is to you
すぐそばにいるの
The closer they are to you
ただ あなたにだけ届いて欲しい
I just want it to reach only you
響け恋の歌
Resonate, song of love
ほら
Look
（歌唱）
(Vocalizing)
響け恋の歌
Let the love song ring out
握りしめた手　離すことなく
Holding hands tightly, never letting go
思いは強く　永遠誓う
Our thoughts are strong, we swear eternity
永遠の淵　きっと僕は言う
On the brink of eternity, I'm sure I'll say
思い変わらず　同じ言葉を
The same words, my feelings unchanged
それでも足りず　涙に変わり
Even then it's not enough, they turn into tears
喜びになり　言葉にできず
They turn into joy, I can't find the words
ただ抱きしめる
I just hold you close
ほら　あなたにとって
Look, for you
大事な人ほど　すぐそばにいるの
The person most important to you is right by your side
ただ　あなたにだけ　届いて欲しい
I just want it to reach only you
響け恋の歌
Let the love song ring out
（歌唱）
(Vocalizing)
夢ならば覚めないで
If it's a dream, don't wake me up
あなたと過ごした時
The time I spent with you
永遠の星となる
Will become an eternal star
ほら　あなたにとって
Look, for you
大事な人ほど　すぐそばにいるの
The person most important to you is right by your side
ただ　あなたにだけ　届いて欲しい
I just want it to reach only you
響け恋の歌
Let the love song ring out
ほら　あなたにとって
Look, for you
大事な人ほど　すぐそばにいるの
The person most important to you is right by your side
ただ　あなたにだけ　届いて欲しい
I just want it to reach only you
響け恋の歌
Let the love song ring out
（歌唱）
(Vocalizing)
響け恋の歌
Let the love song ring out
みんなー！ありがとうー！ありがとうー！
Everyone! Thank you! Thank you!
ここで、一つ、
Here, one thing,
マリンからお知らせがあります。
I have an announcement to make.
え？何か聞いてる？　何？聞いてない。
Eh? Did you hear anything? What? I haven't heard anything.
今日でこのバンドは、
As of today, this band...
解散します！
...is disbanding!
えーーー！？待って！待って！
Eeeee!? Wait! Wait!
嘘でしょ…？
You're kidding, right...?
マリンには、やりたいことがあるんだ。
I have something I want to do.
やりたいこと？やりたいことって何…？
Something you want to do? What do you mean by that...?
みんな、さよなら。
Everyone, goodbye.
え？待って！行かないで！
Eh? Wait! Don't go!
嘘ぺこでしょ…
It's a prank, right-peko...
うわー、マリンどうしてるかな？
I wonder how Marine is doing.
ねー。どっか行っちゃったよね。
Yeah. She just left.
あ、見て見て。
Oh, look, look.
特報
Special News
特別ですよ！
This is special!
アタシ厄介よ
I'm troublesome
港なんかじゃ　はしゃがないわ
I don't frolic at ports or anything
近頃まで　脱がされたの
Until recently, I was stripped
真面目にして欲しい気分
I'm in the mood to be serious
ギュッと合わせて美少女無罪
Press them together, beautiful girl is innocent
キミのイチバン目指して
Aiming to be your number one
夜空　本当は　自信ないけど
The night sky, truth be told, I have no confidence but...
頑張っちゃう！
...I'll do my best!
このあと22時プレミア公開！！
Premiere at 22:00 after this!!
ドキドキしてる？
Is your heart pounding?
いきますよー！
Here we go!
美少女無罪♡パイレーツ
Beautiful Girl is Innocent ♡ Pirates
(美少女無罪！美少女無罪！マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！)
(Beautiful girl is innocent! Beautiful girl is innocent! Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!)
やだキラキラ
No, it's sparkling
またクラクラ
And dizzy again
ねぇ、言ったよね？ねぇ、年齢なんて関係ないってさ。
Hey, you said it, right? Hey, that age doesn't matter.
そういうめんどくさいのも含めて愛してくれるって。
That you'd love me including those troublesome parts.
ねぇ、ねぇ、言ったよね？言ってない？
Hey, hey, you said it, right? You didn't?
ふん、そういうこと言うんだ。ちなみにこの船では美少女無罪が適用されますけど？
Hmph, so you say that. By the way, "Beautiful Girl is Innocent" applies on this ship, you know?
任せて
Leave it to me
魔法で若返り
Rejuvenating with magic
(若返り！若返り！)
(Rejuvenation! Rejuvenation!)
うぶ声はキミにだけ...
Only for you, my first cry...
特別ですよ！
It's special!
あたし焼きたいの
I want to be jealous
港区女子じゃ
Not a Minato-ku girl
はしゃげないわ 近頃はね
I can't frolic lately, you know
だから野島にしてほしい気分
So I feel like I want to be on a desert island
キュンとさせて美少女マリンタイム
Make me feel 'kyun', Bishoujo Marine Time
キミの一番目立たせよ
Let's make you stand out the most
そら本当は
To be honest,
自信ないけど頑張っちゃおう
I'm not confident, but let's do our best
キュキュキュルン キュキュキュルン
Kyu kyu kyunrun Kyu kyu kyunrun
恋する気持ち17歳
Feeling in love, 17 years old
てっぺんになっちゃうわ 大人の時間
It's reaching the peak, adult time
ドキドキしてる？
Is your heart pounding?
まだ早い！
It's too early!
た・た・た だめですか？
T-T-T- Is it no good?
フリルの服着たら
If I wear frilly clothes
そんなことない
That's not true
た・た・た 魔法少女になってみたい
T-T-T- I want to try being a magical girl
キリキリ有罪！
Painfully guilty!
死んだは何歳？
How old was I when I died?
ピリッたは再生性
The period is regeneration
キミももっと若い！
You're much younger too!
何だってするから見捨てないでキミたち
I'll do anything, so don't abandon me, you guys
ドキドキいってみたい
I want to try feeling it pound
たまにいじけちゃ
Sometimes I get sulky,
それでもいいの
but that's fine
年頃だもん 本気にしちゃ
I'm at that age, don't take it seriously
嵐の中も
Even in the middle of a storm,
一緒に行こう！
let's go together!
ハートにチャーブ 美少女マリンタイム
Charm in my heart, Bishoujo Marine Time
あれあれどうした めんどくさい
Oh my, what's wrong? 'It's a bother,'
よなんて言っちゃって
you say that but,
かまってくれるキミが好き
I love that you still pay attention to me
キュキュキュルン キュキュキュルン
Kyu kyu kyunrun Kyu kyu kyunrun
優しくしてね17歳
Be gentle with me, 17 years old
10歩だけ園地 お楽しみ中
Having fun just ten steps into the park
ドキドキしてる？
Is your heart pounding?
まだ早い！
It's too early!
お許しください！
Please forgive me!
このマリンの魅力 魔力 不可抗力！
This Marine's charm, magic, and inevitability!
罪な女ね
A sinful woman, isn't she?
離さないで 捕まっていて
Don't let go, keep holding on
世界の広さ 見せてあげるから
I'll show you how vast the world is
キュンとさせて美少女マリンタイム
Make me feel 'kyun', Bishoujo Marine Time
キミの一番目立たせよ
Let's make you stand out the most
そら冗談も
Even jokes,
大好きだけど真剣よ
I love them but I'm serious
キュキュキュルン キュキュキュルン
Kyu kyu kyunrun Kyu kyu kyunrun
恋する気持ち17歳
Feeling in love, 17 years old
てっぺんになっちゃうわ 大人の時間
It's reaching the peak, adult time
ドキドキしてる？
Is your heart pounding?
まだ早い！
It's too early!
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Innocent! Innocent! Bishoujo's innocent!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine's innocent!
めっぽうキラキラ
Extremely sparkling
もっとクラクラ
Getting more dizzy
マリンじゃなくて...
It's not Marine...
マリン船長だろ！
It's Captain Marine!
はい！ということで早速ですが、
Alright! So without further ado,
今お披露目した船長の新オリジナル曲「美少女無罪♡パイレーツ」は
the Captain's new original song "Bishoujo Muzai♡Pirates" that I just performed,
このあと22時からプレミア公開となっています！
will have its premiere release at 10 PM tonight!
「Unison」「マリ箱」に引き続きのアニメチームに
The same animation team that worked on "Unison" and "Marine Box",
さらに増員して今までで一番すごい映像になったと思います！！
with even more staff added, has created what I think is the most amazing video yet!!
そしてなんと！今回は船長も
And what's more! This time, even the Captain...
人生初のアニメ原画に参加させていただきました！
...participated in creating anime keyframes for the first time in her life!
船長が担当した箇所がどこかぜひ探してみてください！
Please try to find which parts were done by the Captain!
今度答え合わせしましょう！
Let's check the answers later!
楽曲はナナホシ管弦楽団様に書いていただきました！
The song was written by Nanahoshi Orchestra!
マリンの一味へ向けた、ラブソングとなっております。
It's a love song dedicated to Marine's crew.
是非船長の愛を受け取るためにたくさん聴いてください！！
Please listen to it a lot to receive the Captain's love!!
このあと24時からは各種音楽サイトで配信もありますよ～
From midnight tonight, it will also be available on various music streaming sites~
さらにさらになんですが！Amazon Musicさんのプレイリスト
And there's more! On Amazon Music's playlist...
「VIRTUALity」でこの曲をプッシュしてもらえることになりました！！
... "VIRTUALity", this song will be featured!!
キミたちいっぱい聴いてください！
You guys, please listen to it a lot!
そしてなんと！全国のカラオケDAMで
And! At karaoke DAM nationwide...
明日31日から歌えます！早い！
...you can sing it starting tomorrow, the 31st! That was fast!
本人映像（MV）も8月1日から順次配信開始になります！
The original music video will also be available sequentially from August 1st!
ぜひカラオケで仲間に布教してみてください！
Please try to spread the word to your friends at karaoke!
さらに！船長がDAMチャンネルにも出演予定ですので
Also! The Captain is scheduled to appear on DAM Channel...
お楽しみに！
...so look forward to it!
まだあります！あの！
There's still more! Like...
新宿駅東口のクロス新宿ビジョンにて
...on the Cross Shinjuku Vision at the Shinjuku Station East Exit...
「美少女無罪♡パイレーツ」の90秒のMV放映が決定しましたー！！
a 90-second MV clip of "Bishoujo Muzai♡Pirates" will be broadcast!!
新宿駅東口のあの有名な猫ちゃんの所ですね！
It's that famous spot with the cat at Shinjuku Station's East Exit!
期間は8/1～8/15
The period is from 8/1 to 8/15...
7時～25時までですね。
...from 7 AM to 1 AM.
放映時間は日により変更となる場合があるようですが、
The broadcast times may vary by day, but...
毎時1回は放映される予定です！！
...it's scheduled to be shown once every hour!!
最近気温も高いので
The temperature has been high lately, so...
ご覧になる際は体調管理にお気をつけくださいね！
please take care of your health when you go to see it!
もうこんな感じで、お楽しみが目白押しです！
Anyway, there are so many things to look forward to!
もうこんな感じで、お楽しみが盛り沢山なんです！
It's like this, there are so many things to look forward to!
ワクワクしながらいっぱい聴いて待っててくださいね！
Please wait excitedly and listen to it a lot!
続いての告知です！
Next announcement!
実はあの日常侵食ホラーゲーム『つぐのひ』と
Actually, it's been decided that I'll collaborate
マリンがコラボさせて頂けることが決定しました〜！
with the horror game "Tsugunohi"!
そして本日は、なんと！
And today, believe it or not!
今日の配信を見ているキミたちに、開発中の
I'm going to give you guys watching today's stream
ゲーム画面を特別にチラ見せしちゃいます！
a special sneak peek at the game screen under development!
宝鐘海賊団の船長の……宝鐘マリンですぅ……
I'm the captain of the Houshou Pirates... Houshou Marine...
その“美貌”に隠された秘密——
The secret hidden behind that "beauty"——
Steamにて発売決定
Releasing on Steam
海賊船の甲板にいるのは主人公？...って、
Is the one on the deck of the pirate ship the protagonist? Wait,
もししかして樽に入っているのは船長がOL時代に
could it be that what's in the barrels is the cardboard boxes
ボーナスの代わりとして受け取った段ボールみかん！
of oranges the Captain received as a bonus during her OL days!
そんな『美魔女の真実』は
That "The Truth of the Witch" is
2023年8月11日金曜日に発売予定！
scheduled for release on Friday, August 11, 2023!
詳しくはつぐのひ公式アカウントさんをチェックですよ〜！
Be sure to check the official Tsugunohi account for details!
続いてはお楽しみのグッズのおしらせでーす！
Next up is the announcement for the much-awaited merch!
めっちゃほしいものしかないですよ〜 まずはこちら！
It's full of things you'll definitely want! First up is this!
あかさあい先生描きおろしのラバーマットです！
It's a rubber mat illustrated by Akasa Ai-sensei!
机に敷いたりカードゲームしたり飾ったり！
You can put it on your desk, play card games, or display it!
まあ好きにしてください。
Well, do as you like.
海賊の宝の地図風デザインなので
It has a pirate treasure map-style design,
机に置いているだけで船長気分を味わえますよ。
so just by having it on your desk, you can feel like the Captain.
キミも、陸海賊にならないか！？
Won't you become a land pirate too!?
つづいてランダムラバーストラップです！
Next is the random rubber straps!
こちらは船長が描き下ろしました！
These were illustrated by the Captain!
前回はなかった衣装や髪型のものなので、これは欲しいですよね！
They feature outfits and hairstyles that weren't available last time!
がんばって描いたので、ぜひゲットしてください。そしてこれは欲しいでしょう！
I worked hard on the drawings, so please get them. And you'll definitely want this!
おでかけマリンぬいぐるみです！
It's the "Odekake Marine" plushie!
顔面はね、船長が描かせていただいて監修しました！
As for the face, the Captain drew it and supervised it!
かわいい顔で届きますように〜
I hope it reaches you with a cute face~
ちっちゃいぬいぐるみなのでぜひ、持ち運んだり、
It's a small plushie, so please carry it around,
胸の谷間に挟んだり小物入れに入れたりしてください。
stick it in your cleavage, or put it in a small accessory case.
あ、小物入れ、持ってないですか？ なら！！
Oh, you don't have a case? Then!!
これはどうですか！？マリ箱です〜！
How about this!? It's the "Mari-Bako"!
はい、こちら、マリ箱のミュージックビデオに
Yes, this is a reproduction of the box from
出てくる船長が閉じ込められている箱を
the "Mari-Bako" music video where
再現していただきました！
the Captain is trapped inside!
この中にさっきのマリンぬいをぶち込んで遊んだり、
You can play by stuffing the Marine plushie inside,
大切なものをぶち込んだり、
or put your important belongings in it,
飾ったまま一生開けなかったり、
or keep it on display and never open it,
自由に使ってくださいね！
please use it as you like!
こちらすべて購入のフルセット特典は、
The bonus for purchasing the full set is
直筆メッセージ入りポストカードと、
a postcard with a handwritten message, and
船長が、耳を舐めようとしてギリ舐めないASMRボイスがついてきま〜す！
an ASMR voice where the Captain almost licks your ear!
直筆メッセージは数量限定なので、
The handwritten messages are limited in quantity,
なくなり次第、複製メッセージになりますが、こちらも愛を込めて書きますね！
so once they're gone they'll be replaced with copies!
ASMRボイスは絶対ついてくるので、アドしかない！
The ASMR voice is definitely included, so it's a win!
というわけで、このあとは
So, after this,
『美少女無罪♡パイレーツ』の
go and watch the incredible music video for
ものすごいミュージックビデオを見に行ってくださいね！
"Bishoujo Muzai♡Pirates"!
船長が原画描いたところ、探してくださいね〜。
Please look for the parts where the Captain drew the keyframes~.
それでは、いきますよ〜！
Now then, here we go!
出航ーー！！
Set sail!!